

CONTACT

- A https://feranmi.dev
- Lagos, Nigeria

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS, SCSS
- JavaScript
- WAI-ARIA
- React, Next.js, Vue.js
- Webpack, Babel
- Node.js
- React Native
- Technical Writing

EDUCATION

NATIONAL DIPLOMA: COMPUTER SCIENCE

2015

Yaba College of Technology, Lagos, Nigeria.

TRAINING

- Google Africa Developer Scholarship
 Mobile Web Specialist
 - Pluralsight | 2019
- HNG Internship
 Frontend Development
 2019
- DevC Training with Facebook and Andela
 Core track, Web
 OpenClassrooms | 2019

SOCIAL



@uxFeranmi

y @uxFeranmi

o @feranmi.dev

Feranmi Akinlade

Senior Frontend Engineer

ABOUT

I'm a Frontend Engineer with experience in developing responsive, performant and accessible user interfaces. I have a deep understanding of the Open Web Stack of technologies, and I'm passionate about creating satisfying user experiences that are accessible to as many people as possible.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER

Helicarrier | Nov 2021 - Present

As a Senior Engineer, I am leading the architecture and development of Sendcash—a hybrid web and mobile consumer app for cryptocurrency-powered cross-border remittance.

- Set up a frontend architecture optimized for high performance, with code splitting, asset preloading and server-side rendering
- Conducting code reviews, driving a high standard of code quality and user experience
- Pioneered and maintaining internal documentaion of the frontend codebase.
- Evangelizing accessibility standards in product
- Coordinating a distributed team to develop and ship new features in a timely manner
- Providing support and guidance to other team members
- Conducted interviews and worked with the VP of Engineering to find the best talent to grow the Frontend team

FRONTEND ENGINEER

Helicarrier | Jan 2020 - Nov 2021

- Worked across multiple products with a varied tech stack that included React, React Native, Vue.js, Angular, Ionic, Node.js, EJS, and
- Conducted accessibility tests and implement necessary improvements
- Collaborated with peers and stakeholders in a fast-paced distributed team.
- Developed hybrid mobile apps with Ionic and React Native.
- Wrote technical articles for the company blog

WEB DEVELOPER

Freelance | Jan 2019 – Jan 2020

As a freelance web developer my goal was to create an online presence for small businesses, helping them expand their reach.

- Communicating effectively with the client to scope out project requirements
- Created fully responsive layouts, ensuring a great viewing experience for both mobile and desktop users
- Used semantic markup to create accessible web pages
- Consumed third-party REST APIs to facilitate collection of data from users via web forms without a server-side
- Favored the Jamstack principle of prerendered static pages for improved load performance
- Worked with WordPress and the WooCommerce API to build a fully customized UI for an online store